Alberto Alfaro

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER AND DATA ANALYST

CONTACT INFORMATION:

Residence: Mexico City
Cellphone Number: +52 55 3733 2580

Linked-in: https://www.linkedin.com/in/alberto-alfaro/

Github: https://github.com/aalfaro88
E-mail: aalfaro88@gpofinalpa.com
Personal Website https://alberto-alfaro.netlify.app/

ABOUT ME:

I am a professional with a strong foundation in financial planning, pricing strategies, and cashflow management, backed by more than five years of experience. My unique blend of financial expertise and technological proficiency, along with skills in web development and data analytics, positions me as a versatile asset. Alongside my academic achievements, real-world entrepreneurial experience, and a drive for innovation in emerging technologies, I am well-prepared to lead and implement transformative solutions spanning various aspects of an organization, from financial strategies and marketing initiatives to operational efficiency and technology innovations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

PRODIN Founder and Developer Feb 2022 – Present Mexico City

- Founded Tech Company: Launched a tech company, providing innovative software solutions for artists entering the NFT market.
- Successful NFT Project Launch: Successfully launched and sold an NFT project, demonstrating an effective execution within the NFT market.
- Software Development: Developed from scratch an advanced software tool, tailored to empower artists into the NFT market.

ELARA COMUNICACIONES Financial Planning Manager Jul 2015 – Aug 2020 Mexico City

- Developed a robust project evaluation excel model for profit maximization while maintaining competitiveness.
- Contributed to securing a significant project with Mexico's top telecommunications company during the Financial Planning Coordinator tenure.
- Successfully oversaw multiple areas as Financial Planning Manager, ensuring timely information for cash flow analysis and creating comprehensive financial reports.

EDUCATION:

IRONHACK	Web Development and Data Analytics	Dec 2022 - Sep 2023	Miami
IE BUSINESS SCHOOL	Fulltime MBA	Sep 2020 - Dec 2021	Madrid
UNIVERSIDAD IBERO	Industrial Engineer	Sep 2009 – Dec 2014	Mexico City

PROJECTS:

PROJECT NAME	Description	Tools	Links
BITCOIN PREDICTION THROUGH MACHINE LEARNING	This tool was created using Python, Pandas and Machine Learning libraries and it intends to predict the tendency for the next day of the Bitcoin Value.	Python, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Xgboost, Scipy, APIs.	https://github.com/aalfaro88/Bitcoin-Prediction
STACK EXCHANGE API AND FLIGHT INFO SQL	This app was created using Python in flask, and React for the front end. It extracts information from Stack Exchange API and process it through queries, as well as creates an SQL database which then we interact with.	Python, ReactIs, Flask, Docker, CSS, MySQL, APIs	https://github.com/aalfaro88/StackAPI-and-FlightSQL
IMAGE JUMBLE	Full Stack web-app that allows users to generate unique images by uploading and randomizing layered visuals, with the option to download the created collections.	ReactJs, NodeJs, Html5, CSS, MongoDB	 https://image-jumble.netlify.app/ https://github.com/aalfaro88/Image-Jumble-Client https://github.com/aalfaro88/Image-Jumble-Server
BANK SIMULATOR	Full Stack web-app that allows users to simulate bank operations, such as transferring between users or investing.	ReactJs, NodeJs, Html5, CSS, MongoDB	 https://alberto-alfaro.netlify.app/bank-simulator https://github.com/aalfaro88/portfolio- client/blob/main/src/Pages/BankSimulatorHome.jsx https://github.com/aalfaro88/portfolio- server/blob/main/routes/bank.js

SKILLS:

- Modelling: Excel, Google Sheets
- Coding: Python, Javascript, CSS, HTML, MySQL, ReactJS
- Additional: Macros, Docker, API, MongoDB, Flask, NodeJS, Jupyter Notebook, Express, Git, Github, Tableu, PowerBI

LANGUAGES:

Spanish – Native, English - Fluent